Akhilesh Gandotra

iOS Developer

Chandigarh | 7508162163 | akgandotra90@gmail.com

Summary

Passionate engineer with proficient skills. My objective is to learn and use top technology headlines. Very enthusiastic in learning and experimenting. 1 year of experience in iOS Development. Been involved with a lot of different applications like heath care, medical staffing, Voip, on demand delivery, jobs etc.

A **swift** digger, I like to build clean apps with optimised code for better performance and speed.. I do my best to go into clients' tasks to finish projects on time and deliver **maintainable** and **robust** code.

I would like to work in an environment of **growth** and **competition** where I can utilize skill that effectively contributes to the growth of organization.

Professional Experience

iOS Developer

Jul, 2016 - Present

Clicklabs

Served as a **core member** of the iOS Team. **Build** and **completed** applications as per the client. Strategically managed and gave ways to implement functionality in the iOS Apps.

Optimising and refactoring code for enhanced performance.

Debugging code for removing errors.

Contributed in building the **base project** of iOS for the company.

Software intern

Jan, 2016 - Jun, 2016

Clicklabs

Learning about the app architecture and developing apps.

Started working on the live project from the second month.

Enhancing skills in swift and hands on experience on developing apps.

Projects

- Praos Health https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/praos-health/id1229105635
- Clinic World Medical and health care app. On demand doctor patient app. Search doctor by name or location. Can search labrooms too. Can read medical topics and feeds on the app.

Chat and video call implemented.

- Chasing A Day Working model of on demand jobs in Australia. Included punch in, punch
- **FirePie** Pizza delivery app. included Live tracking through sockets. Use of google maps and polylines.

Education

B.E(Electronics and comm.)

2012 - 2016

Skills

Swift

UIKit & Autolayouts

REST & Social API integration

Core Data

Push Notifications

Cocoa Pods

SocketIO

Core Image & Animations

Memory Management

Google maps

VOIP

MapKit & Core Location

Achievements

- Certificate of merit During college.
- Base project A template consisting of various modules for easy implementation of on demand and other iOS apps.
- Wrapper Classes For integration of Social Apis, Sockets, Google maps etc

Hobbies

UIET(Panjab University)

8.6 CGPA

Awarded Certificate of Excellence for merit.

Delhi Public School

Jammu

12th percentage: 90

10th CGPA: 9.8

- Listening songs
- Reading blogs about swift and coding.
- Food lover.

2010 - 2012